Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Certificates 1700-1991 PR 014
New-York Historical Society
- Series XIX: Scientific, 1819-1945
  Award certificates from various environmental, agricultural, and horticultural societies include an award for "a superior market wagon" from the Queens County Agricultural Society, and "best 12 ears of sweet corn" from the Horticultural Society of Morrisania.
  A certificate of membership in the Audubon Society is embellished with an engraved portrait of Audubon as well as a small image of Cedar Birds.
  A hand-lettered certificate by Tiffany and Co. from the American Numismatic and Archaeological Society commemorates the retirement of Daniel Parish, Jr. Tiffany and Co. also designed the membership certificates for the American Museum of Natural History.
  Also of note are certificates from The Literary and Philosophical Society, a scientific society founded by DeWitt Clinton and Samuel Latham Mitchell in New York in 1814, and dissolved 1834.
  - Amateur Astronomers Association, 1947 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1887-1913 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - American Forestry Association, 1927 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
  - American Geographical and Statistical Society, 1856 (Folder FF80)
  - American Institute, 1856, 1885 (Folder FF80)
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1895, 1918-1939 (Folder FF80)
  - American Numismatic and Archaeological Society, 1896 (Folder FF80)
  - Aquidneck Agricultural Society of Newport, Rhode Island, 1881 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks, 1902 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
  - Astronomical Society of Michigan, undated (Folder FF80)
  - Audubon Society, 1887 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  - Federation of the Bird Clubs of New England, 1926 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  - Franklin Institute, 1938 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Horticultural Society of Morrisania, undated (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
  - Horticultural Society of New Haven, 1846 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1945 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Literary and Philosophical Society of New York, 1822, undated (Folder FF80)
  - Massachusetts Kennel Club, 1882 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  - Montgomery County Agricultural Society, circa 1840 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  - National Geographic Society, 1907-1936 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 11)
  - New Jersey Association of Poultry, Pigeon and Pet Stock Fanciers, 1922 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1895 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - New York Zoological Society, 1911-1916 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 12)
  - Patrons of Husbandry, 1896 (Folder FF80)
  - Queens County Agricultural Society, 1849 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Society for the Promoting Agriculture and Domestic Manufactures, 1819-1822 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Westminster Kennel Club, New York, 1879 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
- Series XX: Sports and Athletics, 1800-1933
  This series includes certificates of membership to the Amateur Athletic Union of the United States and the New York Sadlers' Society. Also included is a certificate qualifying Louis Senar as an instructor in the art of fencing from the Amateur Fencers League of America.
  - Amateur Fencers League, undated (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
  - American Athletic Union, 1887, 1933 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
  - New-York Sadler's Society, circa 1800 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
- Series XXI: Trades, 1795-1939
  This series includes certificates of membership to professional societies, as well as one certificate of recognition from the Building Trades Employers' Association.
  Three early certificates are found in this series. One, a membership certificate for the New York Coopers Society dated 1827, is illustrated with an engraving of men working along a harbor. Another, from the Society of Master Sail Makers of the City of New York dated 1795, is illustrated with several vignettes showing sail making, ship building and harbor scenes and has its original wax seal. The third, dated 1825 and printed by Peter Maverick, was given to Sarah Daniels for her "meritorious services" by the Society for the Encouragement of Fathful Domestic Servants.
  A certificate awarded to John Rogers for his statuary groups from the Massachusetts Charitable Mechanic Association is included. Certificates of membership in the General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen, printed by Maverick, include those of John McComb and John Snook. Also included is a lithograph for the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers printed by the Strobridge Lithographing Company.
  - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1899 (Folder FF53)
  - Brotherhood of Local Engineers, 1884 (Folder FF81)
  - Building Trades Employers' Association, 1904 (Folder FF53)
  - General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen, 1791-1878, undated (Folder FF54)
  - Institution of Radio Engineers Australia, 1939 (Folder FF53)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local Union Three, 1939 (Folder FF53)
  - Massachusetts Charitable Mechanic Association, 1874, 1881 (Folder FF53)
  - Mechanics Institute of the City of New York, 1853 (Folder FF53)
  - Mechanics Mutual Protections, 1848 (Folder FF53)
  - Merchant's Association of New York, 1908-1928 (Folder FF55)
  - New York Building Congress, undated (Folder FF53)
  - New York Coopers Society, 1827 (Folder FF53)
  - Society of Master Sail-Makers of the City of New York, 1795 (Folder FF53)
  - Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers, 1893 (Folder FF53)
  - Society for the Encouragement of Faithful Domestic Servants, 1825 (Folder FF53)
- Series XXII: Transportation, 1851-1985
  This series contains certificates of membership and commemoration; licenses; and invitations related to ship, steamboat, and railroad transport.
  One certificate of membership records dues paid to the New York Cheap Transportation Association. Two licenses are included; one to operate motor boats carrying passengers for hire, the other to operate ocean or coastwise steam and motor vessels.
  Two certificates commemorate the opening of the New York and Erie Rail Road. An invitation to attend the ceremony of opening the Holland Tunnel is also included in this series.
  Another certificate is a resolution passed by the Central Park, North and East River Railroad Company thanking police officials for their assistance during a strike.
  Also of interest are two certificates of inspection for the steamers New York and Daniel Drew.
  - Central Park, North and East River Railroad Company, 1889 (Folder FF56)
  - Certificate of Inspection for Passenger Steamers, 1876, 1892 (Folder FF56)
  - Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1985 (Folder FF56)
  - New York Cheap Transportation Association, 1874 (Folder FF56)
  - New York and Erie Railroad Company, 1851 (Folder FF56)
  - New York State Bridge and Tunnel Commission, 1927 (Folder FF56)
  - United States Department of Commerce, 1940-1941 (Folder FF56)